Gates of Imagination Presents The Door in the Wall by Herbert George Wells
Read by Arthur Lane
Chapter 1
One confidential evening, not three months ago, Lionel Wallace told me this story of
the door in the wall, and at the time I thought that so far as he was concerned it was a true
story. He told it me with such a direct simplicity of conviction that I could not do otherwise
than believe in him. But in the morning, in my own flat, I woke to a different atmosphere.
And as I lay in bed and recalled the things he had told me, stripped of the glamour of
his earnest, slow voice, denuded of the focused shaded table light, the shadowy atmosphere
that wrapped about him and the pleasant bright things, the dessert and glasses and napery
of the dinner we had shared, making them for the time a bright little world quite cut off
from everyday realities.